<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news.atom"/>
  <title>Toto Fabrics - Toto Fabrics Blog</title>
  <updated>2018-06-09T02:10:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Toto Fabrics</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/what-are-double-rubs-and-how-many-do-i-need-for-an-upholstery-fabric</id>
    <published>2018-06-09T02:10:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-09T02:15:14-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/what-are-double-rubs-and-how-many-do-i-need-for-an-upholstery-fabric"/>
    <title>What Are Double Rubs and How Many Do I Need For An Upholstery Fabric?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Toto Fabrics</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>What are Double Rubs?</strong></p>
<p>If you are shopping for <a href="www.totofabrics.com" title="Wholesale Upholstery Fabric">upholstery fabric</a> the words ‘double rub’ will keep popping up. Simply put, this is a method for testing the ability of a fabric to withstand wear from abrasion. The test which uses double rubs is called the Wyzenbeek Test or method. This is a mechanized method that involves rubbing a piece of cotton duck on the test fabric. Each back and forth motion of the mechanical arm is called a double rub. This mimics the action of sitting down and getting up, the two actions where fabrics are likely to rub against each other. The double rubs are done in sets of 5,000 until the test fabric shows signs of wear or 2 yarns break. A notable change in color and pile are also noted. Typically, 3,000 double rubs are estimated to be one year’s use.</p>
<p><strong>How do the amount of double rubs affect the durability of a fabric?</strong></p>
<p>The biggest cause of wear and tear in upholstery fabrics is abrasion. This occurs as people shift in their seats, for example, or move their backs on the support of a chair. A fabric that wears out easily is not very suitable for high traffic areas like public waiting rooms in government offices. Typically, a fabric is labelled heavy duty if it can withstand 15,000+ double rubs. The level of abrasion resistance in a fabric determines the way it can be used. For residential purposes; • Delicate duty – Under 3,000 double rubs. This type of fabric is suitable for use in pillows, drapes and curtains. • Light duty – 3,000-9,000 double rubs. Suitable for use on occasional use furniture • Medium duty – 9,000-15,000 double rubs. This type of fabric is more versatile and can be used on different daily-use furniture • Heavy duty – 15,000+ double rubs. Suitable for the favorite family couch in the living room For commercial purposes • Contract upholstery fabric – 15,000-20,000 double rubs. This is used on furniture that is in light traffic areas, for example, the CEO’s waiting room or a tax consultant’s office. These are areas that don’t see many visitors in a day. • Heavy duty - Up to 30,000 double rubs. Suitable for use in areas that see typical business traffic e.g. hotel rooms, conference rooms and dining areas as well as single shift offices • Extra heavy duty - Over 30,000 double rubs. This is for very heavy traffic areas including airport terminals, fast food restaurants, hospital waiting rooms, and government offices, entertainment facilities like bars, stadiums and theaters.</p>
<p><strong>Is the Wyzenbeek test adequate?</strong></p>
<p>This Wyzenbeek could be said to the best indicator of a fabric’s durability because it tests for resistance to the number one factor in wearing down a fabric, which is abrasion. However, it should be noted that a fabric’s durability is also affected by exposure to heat and damp. A fabric like faux leather is able to withstand abrasion very well but is highly susceptible to heat. Faux leather that is exposed to the sun tends to stiffen and crack. Cotton, which is a natural fiber is prone to moisture damage. Cotton that retains moisture will see the growth of mold and fungi, which break down the fabric. Other factors that affect a fabric’s durability include the way the fibers are woven and the content of the fiber. Synthetic fibers generally have more resistance to abrasion than natural fibers. Placement considerations The placement of the furniture is perhaps the other big consideration to be made. Indoor furniture is not exposed to weather extremes of heat and cold. On the other hand, <a href="www.totofabrics.com/collections/all/outdoor-fabric" title="Outdoor Upholstery Fabric">outdoor upholstery fabric</a> has to withstand abrasion and weather extremes and requires a fabric that is resistant to multiple factors. The level of care for a fabric is also a big determinant. <strong>Cleaning the fabric in the right manner has a big impact on its lifespan.</strong></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/79950401-3-great-reasons-to-buy-discount-drapery-fabric</id>
    <published>2015-11-27T17:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-12-11T17:01:24-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/79950401-3-great-reasons-to-buy-discount-drapery-fabric"/>
    <title>3 Great Reasons To Buy Discount Drapery Fabric</title>
    <author>
      <name>Toto Fabrics</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Here are Toto Fabrics we take care of a lot of people who are searching for just the right discount drapery fabric. Why are so many people changing their drapes? Because they can! Here are three great reasons why we have people coming back against and again buying our discount drapery fabric.</p>
<p><b>It’s Fun and Easy! </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">- Many people might balk at the idea of reupholstering a chair, simply because there are so many cuts and everything has to come together so perfectly. Plus, everything has to be taut so that there’s no sagging or ripples. When it comes to drapes, they just hang there! Sure, it’s not quite that easy, but tackling a drape project is one of the easier fabric adventures you can embark on. If you’re just learning to sew, drapes are an excellent start.</span></p>
<p><b>It’s Cheap! </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">- Taking care of making your own drapes isn’t just cheaper than getting them from the store...it’s cheap, period! With just a few yards of fabric you can cover your windows. When you’re buying our discount fabrics online, you’ll get a great deal and be able to change your drapes whenever you want. Be sure to change your drapes whenever you paint. And why not make four sets and swap them out with the seasons?</span></p>
<p><b>The Selection: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you go to a local store, you might have a couple of hundred fabric options, and only some of them might be suitable for drapery. Even their catalogs won’t have a great selection, and you end up not getting just what you want. Here at Toto Fabrics we’ve got an amazing selection of discount drapery fabrics so that you’ll find the perfect fabric for you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Far too many people keep their drapes for years or decades. There’s no reason you shouldn’t be changing your drapes all the time, simply because it’s fun and cheap to do. When you’re looking for a great selection of drapery fabric at amazing prices, <a href="http://www.totofabrics.com/search?type=product&amp;amp;q=drapery" target="_blank">click right here</a>!</span></p>
<strong><br><br><br></strong>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/79921985-discount-upholstery-fabric-or-cheap-upholstery-fabric-call-it-like-it-is</id>
    <published>2015-11-19T12:19:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-12-11T12:18:47-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/79921985-discount-upholstery-fabric-or-cheap-upholstery-fabric-call-it-like-it-is"/>
    <title>Discount Upholstery Fabric or Cheap Upholstery Fabric...Call It Like It Is!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Toto Fabrics</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here at Toto Fabrics, we sometimes get asked if we mind certain terms...terms like “discount” or “cheap upholstery fabric.” After all, people like saying things like “I got an amazing </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">discount </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">on this bag” or “I got that suit for so</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> cheap</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.” Unfortunately, sometimes words like </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">cheap</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> can lead some to think we’re talking about the quality, when we’re really just referring to the price.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, let’s make a few things perfectly clear!</span></p>
<p><b>You’re getting the same high-quality fabric:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Trust us, there’s nothing cheaply-made about our fabric. You’ll be getting the same high-quality drapery and upholstery fabric as you would from other online fabric shops or brick and mortar stores. The main difference is in the price, which might make you wonder how we can offer such huge discounts. Well...</span></p>
<p><b>We work fabric suppliers to get the best price:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Over the decades we’ve been in business, we’ve developed relationships with the top fabric manufacturers in the industry. That alone doesn’t get us the best prices, but the amount that we buy from them year after year guarantees that we can get great deals and pass those amazing discounts on to you.</span></p>
<p><b>Call it like it is!: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">While we keep the quality up, we can’t deny it...our fabric doesn’t cost much! We start at 75% off MSRP for our discount upholstery, and then often offer discounts on top of that! We have steep discounts on fabric remnants, and you can even request free fabric samples!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’re proud to be your go-to source of whole fabric online, and also proud of the quality of the fabric we offer. Find the perfect fabric for you right here at Toto Fabrics!</span></p>
<strong><strong><br></strong></strong>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/79921857-the-advantages-of-crypton-fabric</id>
    <published>2015-11-11T12:15:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-12-11T12:16:11-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/79921857-the-advantages-of-crypton-fabric"/>
    <title>The Advantages of Crypton Fabric</title>
    <author>
      <name>Toto Fabrics</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>In the textile industry, Crypton fabric is one of most amazing fabrics of the past century. While it started out to be much less comfortable, processes have improved since it was introduced in 1993 so that many soft fabrics can go through the Crypton process and come out with all the advantages mentioned below.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So what makes these modern upholstery fabrics so amazing, and why does it work so well in many applications?</span></p>
<p><b>It’s Resistant:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> You know, when we start going down this list we start to wonder why everything in our lives isn’t made from Crypton fabric! First of all, it’s moisture resistant, so liquids just bead up on it so that you can wipe it away. It also resists stains, mildew, bacteria, and odor.</span></p>
<p><b>It’s Permanent:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The process to turn fabrics into Crypton fabric isn’t a spray-on application or a dip or anything like that. The process involves introducing the Crypton copolymer to the fabric so that it actually becomes part of the fabric and cannot be removed. This attribute makes it a perfect solution in instances where a fabric has to stand up to harsh cleaners or when antimicrobial finishes are later applied.</span></p>
<p><b>It’s Environmentally Friendly: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">All of this and it’s pretty darn green, too! Crypton doesn’t use “chemicals” in the traditional sense, and it contains no VOC’s (volatile organic compounds) or formaldehyde.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kind of makes you want buy stock in Crypton, doesn’t it? If not, maybe just some Crypton fabric, then? We can handle that second request! Check out our great selection of Crypton fabric and fabric remnants <a href="http://www.totofabrics.com/collections/crypton-fabric" target="_blank">right here</a>!</span></p>
<br><br>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/78672769-three-ways-to-use-outdoor-upholstery-fabric-in-new-ways</id>
    <published>2015-11-03T10:48:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-12-03T10:49:04-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/78672769-three-ways-to-use-outdoor-upholstery-fabric-in-new-ways"/>
    <title>Three Ways To Use Outdoor Upholstery Fabric In New Ways</title>
    <author>
      <name>Toto Fabrics</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Whenever people hear the words “outdoor upholstery furniture” most of them think of your standard wicker base and the cushions that go on them. They’re usually ones you bring inside so that they aren’t subject to the snow and ice all winter when you can’t use them (at least that’s what we do here in the midwest!)</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But upholstery fabric isn’t just for those few cushions. Here are a few ideas for outdoor upholstery furniture that you might not have thought of:</span></p>
<p><b>Patio Umbrellas: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Patio umbrellas will give out over time, mostly because they’re exposed to so many UV rays from the sun. After they become weak, all it takes is one big gust of wind when it’s open for it to tear and become useless. When that happens you’re in luck, because now you get to pick your new fabric! Sounds like a good winter project to us!</span></p>
<p><b>Pillows: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most outdoor furniture is just so-so when it comes to comfort, and most sets from the store don’t come with comfortable pillows. Make your furniture something you can’t wait to get home to by adding a bunch of comfy pillows!</span></p>
<p><b>Bring it indoors: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Outdoor upholstery fabric indoors? What, are we crazy? Well, if you have a four season porch, outdoor fabric is a great transition between the inside and the outside. It can take the cold better and can also be moved outdoors quickly if you need additional seating.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Outdoor upholstery fabric certainly has its uses beyond the obvious ones. Find the best from Toto Fabrics <a href="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a%20href=%22http://www.totofabrics.com/collections/outdoor-fabric%22&gt;&lt;span%20style=%22font-weight:%20400;%22&gt;http://www.totofabrics.com/collections/outdoor-fabric&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;%20&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" target="_blank">right here</a>!</span></p>
<strong><strong><br></strong></strong>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/77015361-we-love-it-when-customers-show-us-what-they-ve-done-with-our-discount-upholstery-fabric</id>
    <published>2015-10-24T17:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-11-16T15:57:04-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/77015361-we-love-it-when-customers-show-us-what-they-ve-done-with-our-discount-upholstery-fabric"/>
    <title>We Love It When Customers Show Us What They’ve Done With Our Discount Upholstery Fabric!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Toto Fabrics</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Sometimes walking around our warehouse can lead to a certain wistfulness. After all, we’re surrounded by hundreds of thousands of yards of thousands of beautiful fabrics, and yet we seldom get to see what people have done with it.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But we want to change that! We truly want to see what you’ve been doing with our discount upholstery fabric, and that’s why we have an Instagram account where you can upload photos of your most recent project using our upholstery fabric. </span></p>
<p><b>Show off!</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> - Toto Fabrics is one of the largest suppliers of upholstery fabric online. Put up your photos and you’ll be featured on the national site of a huge fabric store!</span></p>
<p><b>Inspire others!</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> - Most of us have that piece of furniture sitting around that we’ve been threatening to re-cover for years. When you put up a picture of your latest creation, it will inspire others to do the same. And that will brighten their lives as well!</span></p>
<p><b>Make us feel good! </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">- Like we said, sometimes we feel like a vegetarian at a BBQ joint...it looks good, but there’s just nothing we can do about it! Even if we upholstered one item a day, it would take decades to get through the upholstery fabric we have...and that’s assuming that we never get any new stock! We’d love to live vicariously through you, so send in pics of your latest!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Please let us know how you’ve used our product. You can even upload more than one photo to show us “before and after” shots of your most recent project. <a href="http://www.totofabrics.com/pages/customer-photos" target="_blank">Find out all about how to do it here</a>.  </span></p>
<br><br>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/77015233-why-we-still-offer-free-fabric-samples-here-at-toto-fabric</id>
    <published>2015-10-16T16:57:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-11-16T15:54:01-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/77015233-why-we-still-offer-free-fabric-samples-here-at-toto-fabric"/>
    <title>Why We Still Offer Free Fabric Samples Here At Toto Fabric</title>
    <author>
      <name>Toto Fabrics</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>It’s getting harder and harder to find free fabric samples anywhere. What once was standard practice is becoming more and more rare, especially from online upholstery fabric stores.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Toto Fabrics is one of the last hold-outs when it comes to free fabric swatches. That’s because we want you to get the absolute best discount fabrics online, and one of the best ways to know if it will be the best fabric for you is to hold it and touch it, whether it’s crypton fabric or nylon. So why have so many others upholstery fabric stores fallen away?</span></p>
<p><b>It’s takes a lot of time:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The biggest reason that most places have stopped offering free shipping is because of the time that it takes. When you have thousands (and thousands and thousands) of fabrics like we do, it takes time to head up and down the aisles looking for the right one, cutting a fabric sample, head back to the shipping center, pack it up, and get the right address on the label. That’s a lot of person-power. And speaking of shipping...</span></p>
<p><b>It costs a bundle in shipping:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> As much as we wish there were a “fabric rate” for shipping fabric as there’s a rate for shipping books, there’s just no such thing! We’re shipping these fabric swatches to you free because we want to make sure you get exactly what you want. It’s costs a lot.</span></p>
<strong><strong><br></strong></strong>
<p><b>BUT…!</b></p>
<strong><strong><br></strong></strong>
<p><b>We Want Your Business!:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Let’s be honest here...we’re a business and we want to sell you the best designer upholstery fabric available. And we’ll do what it takes to get your business.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So when you really want to make sure you’re getting the perfect discount upholstery fabric, feel it in your hand by requesting up to 12 of our free fabric samples from any product page. You’ll be glad you did!</span></p>
<strong><strong><br></strong></strong>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/77015105-where-do-fabric-remnants-from-a-wholesale-fabric-supplier-come-from</id>
    <published>2015-10-08T16:52:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-11-16T15:49:58-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/77015105-where-do-fabric-remnants-from-a-wholesale-fabric-supplier-come-from"/>
    <title>Where Do Fabric Remnants From a Wholesale Fabric Supplier Come From?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Toto Fabrics</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Are you into fabric remnants? Considering the amazing deals you can get on them, lots of people are. Most of them realize that just because something isn’t made anymore doesn’t mean it’s out of style! So where do fabric remnants come from?</p>
<p><b>Constant turnover:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Cloth styles are popular and can stick around for years...but specific cloth patterns are retired all the time. Whether we’re talking about cloth for clothing or designer upholstery fabric, fashion will always look to the future in order to get people to buy the latest and greatest. So when we’re down the the last few yards of something, it becomes a bargain while still being as beautiful as ever.</span></p>
<p><b>The Supplier Goes Out Of Business:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> While we’ve established relationships with top manufactures in order to get our modern upholstery fabric, and there are times when a supplier simply goes out of business. In this case, everything eventually becomes a remnant as we sell the bulk of it and there’s no chance of resupply.</span></p>
<p><b>We Buy Them From Another Store:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> We have to admit it, fabric remnants can be hard work. We have to have the space for them, keep them in our inventory, and cut and ship them even if we can’t sell that much of it (they’re remnants, after all!) But we love fabric and want to make sure it gets its full use, so sometimes we buy from other shops that just don’t want it around anymore (that’s why every so often you’ll see “unknown fabric” on one of our fabric remnants).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What it comes down to when you’re buying fabric remnants from a wholesale fabric supplier is this: If you like it, you like it, so buy it! And buy it now, because once fabric remnants are gone they’re gone for good. Shop for remnants right here.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/49261377-top-3-things-people-do-with-our-fabric-remnants</id>
    <published>2015-09-30T09:35:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-10-16T09:34:29-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/49261377-top-3-things-people-do-with-our-fabric-remnants"/>
    <title>Top 3 Things People Do With Our Fabric Remnants</title>
    <author>
      <name>Toto Fabrics</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<strong><br></strong>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’ve mentioned before and it’s probably not the last time you’ll hear it...we have a lot of fabric remnants. Maybe more than any other fabric store online. So we have a lot of people stopping by to take a look at the great deals we have on fabric remnants that will probably never be seen again.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While some of us buy fabric just because we like the pattern and have little idea what we’ll ever do with it (guilty!), here are the top three projects people undertake with our fabric remnants.</span></p>
<p><b>Quilting</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> - Quilting is one of the most common things people do with our discount fabric. Have enough scraps, free fabric samples, and fabric remnants lying about and you’ll eventually make a quilt! While many of these remnants might not cover a couch, they are perfect for quilting.</span></p>
<p><b>Pillows:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The great thing about pillows is that they don’t require much fabric, and the fabric they do require doesn’t have to match the fabric of the of the piece of furniture you’ll be putting them on. Well, perhaps they should match stylistically, but they can be of a completely different material, color, and pattern to add that “pop” to the room.</span></p>
<p><b>Baby Blanket:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> When you have fabric remnants, you might not have enough for a king-size bed. Or queen, or double, or single. But if you see a beautiful piece of remnant that a baby would love to feel against his or her skin, why not make it into a baby blanket?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of course there are thousands of other projects you can do with fabric remnants, and maybe someday we’ll offer up some suggestions. Take a look at our fabric remnants and start your next project!</span></p>
<strong><strong><br></strong></strong>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/49260097-the-advantages-of-buying-wholesale-upholstery-fabric-from-a-specialist</id>
    <published>2015-09-24T09:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-10-16T09:30:19-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/49260097-the-advantages-of-buying-wholesale-upholstery-fabric-from-a-specialist"/>
    <title>The Advantages Of Buying Wholesale Upholstery Fabric From A Specialist</title>
    <author>
      <name>Toto Fabrics</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s no secret...we’re not the only discount upholstery fabric supplier online. In fact, there are some really big names out there who are selling fabric, the guys known as Big Box Stores. You know, the ones who sell </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">everything</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While we might not be the biggest name on the web, we certainly are specialists who’ve been at this for decades. So why would we suggest that, when you’re looking for discount fabrics online, you go with us?</span></p>
<p><b>Our prices:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Many of those huge stores have okay prices, but they’re not buying in the huge amounts that we are. How can we prove this? Because we’re offering everything at 75% off MSRP, something even they can’t do. We even offer discounts on top of our regular steep discount.</span></p>
<p><b>We know fabrics:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Perhaps our greatest strength is that we know fabrics. If you’re not sure about how a certain fabric will work for your project, just contact us. We can confirm that it will work, or we’ll be able to suggest a better one. We doubt you’ll get that level of service from one of the Big Box Stores.</span></p>
<p><b>Our free fabric samples:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Many fabric stores online don’t offer free fabric swatches. And if they do, they don’t just give them to you...they expect you to return them. At Toto, we want you to know exactly what you’re getting, so we will send you up to 12 free fabric sample from anything we have in the store. Shipping is also free!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can buy fabrics lots of places, but we hope you’ll take advantage of all the advantages working with Toto Fabrics for all of your discount upholstery fabric needs. </span></p>
<strong><strong><br></strong></strong>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/49011713-3-great-things-about-fabric-remnants</id>
    <published>2015-09-08T17:25:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-10-15T17:23:08-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/49011713-3-great-things-about-fabric-remnants"/>
    <title>3 Great Things About Fabric Remnants</title>
    <author>
      <name>Toto Fabrics</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Here at Toto Fabrics, we’re one of the largest fabric suppliers online. And where we stand out more than any other place is in the sheer amount of fabric remnants we have (not to mention the amount of sheer fabric remnants we have!). What makes fabric remnants so appealing to so many people?</p>
<p><b>You’ve got variety like never before:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Because we keep so many fabric remnants instead of pitching them, we’ve got a larger selection than nearly any wholesale fabric supplier. Looking at fabric remnants is like looking into the past. Most of the time it’s not looking that far into the past, though, so many of the discount upholstery fabrics we have are fabric remnants that might be just a year old...certainly new enough if you want to save some money. Speaking of which...</span></p>
<p><b>You’ll get a great price:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> At Toto Fabrics, we already have most fabrics at 75% off MSRP. What you might not realize is that you can get that good a deal (or better) when you pick some of our fabric remnant cloth. You want it, we want to move it along. In fact, we hope you’ll take it all. So...</span></p>
<p><b>You’d better act fast:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Many of the fabrics we have are still being made. But when you find the perfect fabric remnants you want for a project, don’t delay...because once they’re gone, they’re gone, and finding it again might take a lifetime. When you find one you love, just drop the whole thing in your cart, because otherwise you’ll never see it again.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fabric remnants are one of those specialties that not all online fabric stores want to deal with. But we’re more than happy to offer you an incredible selection here at Toto. Find <a href="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a%20href=%22http://www.totofabrics.com/collections/remnants%22&gt;&lt;span%20style=%22font-weight:%20400;%22&gt;http://www.totofabrics.com/collections/remnants&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;%20&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" target="_blank">our remnants here</a> and find the perfect cloth for you.</span></p>
<strong><strong><br></strong></strong>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/34702017-the-3-biggest-reasons-people-order-upholstery-fabric-online</id>
    <published>2015-05-28T09:38:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-18T09:40:29-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/34702017-the-3-biggest-reasons-people-order-upholstery-fabric-online"/>
    <title>The 3 Biggest Reasons People Order Upholstery Fabric Online</title>
    <author>
      <name>Bobby Shell</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Fabric stores have been around for more than 100 years, but the last 20 years have brought huge changes to the industry. First, big box stores started selling a small selection of fabric, then the internet came around and changed everything. For Toto Fabrics, we’ve embraced the internet so that we can become your source for discount fabrics online!</p>
<p>So with the options available, why do most people like you opt to buy their upholstery fabric online?</p>
<p><b>Selection </b>- Big box stores have a fabric department, but the selection is okay at best. Craft stores have a pretty good selection, but they’re selling a lot more than fabrics, and space is always a limitation. But for Toto Fabrics, the selection is through the roof, with thousands of  quality upholstery and drapery fabrics to choose from. We do one thing and we do it right, including offering fabric remnants and free fabric swatches.</p>
<p><b>Price </b>- We can offer you better prices for the same reason that Amazon can offer pet supplies at better prices...when you’re doing this in bulk, you get better prices that you can pass on to customers. Nearly all of the wholesale upholstery fabric on our site is 75% off MSRP...even more when you get to the <a href="http://www.totofabrics.com/collections/daily-special" target="_blank">sale</a> and our <a href="http://www.totofabrics.com/collections/clearance-fabrics" target="_blank">clearance items</a>. You’re not going to find a better prices on such high-quality designer upholstery fabric anywhere else!</p>
<p><b>Ease </b>- We love fabric, so we understand the interest in browsing in a fabric store. But we also understand the ease that a well-organized web site can give you. Why drag bolts around a store when you can compare them simply by tossing them in your cart? Or just click a button and you’ll get free fabric samples from any of our designer upholstery fabric.</p>
<strong><br></strong>When you’re looking for excellent upholstery fabric online at the best possible price, Toto Fabrics is your best option for discount fabrics online!]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/17679101-toto-fabrics-family-founders</id>
    <published>2015-04-16T20:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-12T15:57:03-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totofabrics.com/blogs/news/17679101-toto-fabrics-family-founders"/>
    <title>Toto Fabrics, Family Founders</title>
    <author>
      <name>Pasilobus Support</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p class="p1" style="float: left;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0804/7909/files/toto_1951_large.jpg?14290104467337096062"></p>
<p class="p1" style="float: left;">Since 1951, the Marks family has done business in Toto, Indiana. Beginning from one store, Jack and Alma Marks built several stores in the heart of Toto. Their son, Sidney, continued to expand the business in the 1970s and 1980s, selling shoes, clothing, draperies, and records, as well as, of course, fabrics. In the face of the changing business environment and the increased competition of large box stores, Sidney reluctantly closed the bricks and mortar stores in the early 2000s. After trying several experiments, in 2008 he started newtotostores.com and began selling discount upholstery, drapery, and home décor fabrics. Since his death in 2010, his wife, Joan, a retired teacher, and his son, Elliot, have worked with the staff in Toto, Indiana, to maintain the quality standard of the family business set by Sidney. New Toto Stores is now <strong><a href="http://www.totofabrics.com/" title="New Toto Stores now Toto Fabrics an Online Discount Decor Fabric Store">Toto Fabrics</a></strong>, a leading source of discount <span>décor</span> fabrics online.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
